A Finding Aid to the Thomas Anshutz Papers, circa 1870-1942, in the Archives of American Art AAA.anshthom
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1880-1904, 1936 and undated; Series 5; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 1-3, MGP 2; (Boxes 1-4; 2.4 linear feet)
  - Photographs by Thomas Anshutz, 1890s; 5.2
    - Domestic Scenes, 1890s; (10 glass plate negatives housed in Boxes 3 and MGP 2; includes 1 vintage print) (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
      (pictured are women, child, man, dogs, and cats; set by house, in yard)
    - Beach and Water Scenes, 1890s; (6 glass plate negatives housed in Boxes 3 and MGP 2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Cows, undated; (8 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 2; includes 1 vintage print) (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Model in Roman Costume, undated; (1 glass plate negative housed in Box 3) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Portraits, 1890s, undated; (4 glass plate negatives housed in Boxes 3 and MGP 2; 1 cyanotype) (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
      (includes David Wilson Jordan and Anshutz with infant son)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 31 Glass negatives (Box 3)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 18 Glass negatives (Box MGP 2)
  - Unattributed Photographs, 1895, 1897, 1936 and undated; 5.3
    Photographs in this series consist of 92 vintage albumen or cyanotype prints, both mounted and unmounted. Some are similar in subject matter and format to those attributed to the Circle of Anshutz and Eakins, and others bear more similarity to the later photographs made by Anshutz. Despite similarities, however, images in this series have not been directly associated with the photography of Eakins and his circle or with Anshutz as have the photographs above. Due to this ambiguity and lack of identifying information on the photographs themselves, they have not been attributed.
    Several unidentified individuals, interior spaces, and furnishings re-appear in portraits and groups, and may depict family and friends of Anshutz. Occasionally multiple prints are mounted on a single backing; in these cases, they have been counted as a single print.
    - Male Nudes, undated; (2 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - Portraits, undated; (33 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 20-25)
    - Groups, 1897, 1936, undated; (14 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 26-28)
      (Anshutz possibly pictured)
    - Animals, undated; (12 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 29-31)
    - Landscapes, Exteriors, and Views, 1895, undated; (21 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 32-34)
    - Beach and Water Scenes, undated; (4 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Interiors and Furnishings, undated; (6 vintage prints) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Professional Studio Portraits, 1904, undated; 5.4
    This series includes 11 photographs taken in professional photographers' studios and mounted on commercially-stamped backing. A few individuals are identified, including one photograph of Thomas Eakins, and another of E.P. Anshutz, Thomas Anshutz's brother.
    - Thomas Eakins by Geo. and Wm. H. Rau, undated (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
    - E.P. Anshutz by Chandler and Sheetz, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Elizabeth Davis Rogers by Gray, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cow from "Studies from Nature" Series by Schreiber, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified Women by Sarony, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified Men by Geo. and Wm. H. Rau, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified Child, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Anshutz and Works of Art, undated; 5.5
    This series includes twelve prints that appear to have been made at a later time, including a portrait of Anshutz, Anshutz painting a sitter's portrait, Anshutz's studio, a group photograph of the Philadelphia Sketch Club, and six reproductions of drawings of Harper's Ferry by Anshutz. Some of the photographs are annotated by Anshutz's son, Edward Anshutz.
    - Photographs of Anshutz and His Studio, undated (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
    - Group Photograph, Philadelphia Sketch Club, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Drawings of Harper's Ferry, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)